sonybmg.com 2011-06-24

# SONY MUSIC ENTERTAINMENT PRIVACY POLICY | Sony Music Entertainment

Sony Music Entertainment ("Sony Music") and the information collected on this site may be used in the manner described below by Sony Music, our labels, agents, subsidiaries, trusted partners and affiliates acting on our behalf.

When this Privacy Policy uses the term "personal information," we mean information that identifies a particular individual, such as full name, street address, telephone number or email address.

Sony Music is a member of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because Sony Music wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its data collection and privacy practices to TRUSTe for compliance review. We encourage you to review the entire policy. Please click on any of the links below to review that particular section.

* * *

Collection and Use of Personal Information

* * *

**Collection and Use of Personal Information**

We may collect the following personal information from you:

  * Contact information such as name, email address, street address, and phone number
  * Billing information such as credit card number and billing address
  * Demographic information such as age, gender, interests, country and zip code
  * Unique identifiers such as user name and password
  * Preference and other information such as product wish lists, order history, marketing preferences and cell phone carrier

We or one of our trusted partners may use this information to:

  * Send you requested updates and newsletters about an artist, type of music or related special offers
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Send a one-time email or e-card to your friends upon your request when you provide their email address
  * Fulfill your order
  * Send you an order confirmation
  * Respond to customer service requests, questions and concerns
  * Administer your account
  * Process information submitted with a job application
  * Send you marketing communications
  * Administer promotions and sweepstakes you enter and notify you of the results
  * Improve our marketing efforts
  * Conduct research and analysis
  * Display content based upon your interests

We also automatically collect information about your computer as you browse our site(s). Please see the Tracking Technologies section of this Privacy Policy.

**Social Networks/Online Communities**

We enable you to create a profile for accessing blogs or online communities for sharing information such as messages, photos and videos. Please note that we cannot control the actions of others with whom you may choose to share your pages and information. We may also enable you to post content from some of our sites to your profile on other social networks. You can access these services from our sites using Facebook Connect, Twitter, or other Open ID providers. These services will authenticate your identity and allow you to post and share certain personal or other information with that site. Please be aware that the privacy policy of that site will apply to any content you provide them in these instances. We do not allow these services to provide any personal information or content back to our sites or your profile with us unless you agree.

**Transactions**

You may purchase artists' music or merchandise from some of our site(s). We use the personal information you provide in connection with a purchase to process and fulfill your order. This Privacy Policy applies to any such purchases. In some instances, you may be directed to a third party site to initiate your transaction. These third party sites will be clearly identified and link to their own privacy policies so you know which company is collecting your personal information. You should refer to those policies for any privacy-related concerns regarding your purchase with them.

**Information Sharing**

We will share your personal information with third parties in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy.

We may provide your personal information to companies that help us with our business activities such as processing credit card transactions, shipping your order, assisting us in site operations, providing customer service and delivering email newsletters. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services.

We may also share your personal information:

  * With Sony Music affiliates and representatives of our current recording artists
  * With reputable third parties in whose products or services we think you may have an interest, with your prior consent to do so
  * With representatives of former recording artists, who will be advised in advance that your consent is required for continued use
  * As required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process
  * When we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud or respond to a government request
  * In connection with a corporate change including a merger, acquisition or sale of assets
  * To any other third party with your prior consent to do so

**Choice/Opt-Out**

You may choose to stop receiving newsletters, updates or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails. Some sites also allow you to change your email preferences within your online profile.

If you choose to join a mobile marketing list, please be aware that there are usually costs associated with receiving SMS (text) or MMS (multimedia) messages depending on your wireless carrier and plan. You should check with your mobile carrier to determine what charges apply before signing up to receive our updates via your mobile phone. If you would like to stop receiving messages from us on your mobile phone, please reply to the message with "STOP." You may also contact your wireless carrier for additional information on receiving or stopping mobile messages.

**Tracking Technologies**

We automatically collect information as you browse our site(s) such as the domain name, Internet Service Provider, browser type and version, operating system and device type, average time spent on our site(s), pages viewed, information accessed, the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet and other relevant statistics. Such information is sometimes referred to as web analytics and/or clickstream data.

We and our third party partners may use cookies and/or pixel tags to keep track of your visits, preferences and profile information. These may be used to enhance your experience on the site(s) including allowing you to remain logged in on the site(s). Cookies and pixel tags may also be used to collect general usage and aggregated statistical information that does not identify you personally. However, we and our third party partners may use cookies to store some of your preferences (including limited personal information) or to display content based upon what you view on our site(s) in order to personalize your visit with relevant advertising. To learn more about the use of cookies in online advertising, including how to manage or delete them [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/learn_more.asp).

We and some of our third party partners use Flash cookies to store some of your preferences or personal information. For more information on Flash cookies and how to manage privacy and storage settings [click here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html).

**Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive billing information on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). If you choose to use a third party payment option to pay for your order, its privacy statement and security practices will apply to your information. We encourage you to read that privacy statement before providing your information.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and after receipt. However, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Updating Your Personal Information**

Our sites may offer different methods for updating your personal information. To review and update your personal information on artist marketing sites, please log in to your profile/account on each site where you have registered.

To update your billing or shipping information for purchases, please follow the customer service instructions in your order confirmation email.

**Additional Information**

Widgets - Our site(s) may include interactive mini-programs that provide specific services from another company (e.g., displaying digital news feeds), often referred to as widgets. You may have the opportunity to submit personal information, such as your email address, for collection through a widget. Browser or Flash cookies may also be set by a widget to enable it to function properly. Information collected by a widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it.

Links to Other Site(s) - Our site(s) includes links to other site(s) whose privacy practices may differ from those of Sony Music. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any site you visit.

Children – We do not attempt to collect any personal information from those under the age of 13. If you feel that we have unknowingly collected information from someone under the age of 13, please [contact us](http://www.sonymusic.com/about/feedback.php) immediately and this information will be removed.

For more information on how to protect your children online:

**Visit  [www.OnGuardOnline.gov](http://www.onguardonline.gov/) for social networking safety tips for [parents](http://www.onguardonline.gov/topics/social-networking-sites.aspx)[](http://www.onguardonline.gov/topics/social-networking-sites.aspx) and [youth](http://www.onguardonline.gov/topics/safety-tips-tweens-teens.aspx).**

**Changes To This Policy**

By using our site(s), you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will send an email to users who have provided an email address or post a notice on our site(s) prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**Questions About This Privacy Policy**

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, you should first contact Sony Music. You can contact us about this Privacy Policy by writing us:

Sony Music Entertainment   
550 Madison Avenue, Room 2356   
New York, NY 10022

Or you can [click here](http://www.sonymusic.com/about/feedback.php) to submit feedback online

If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe by [clicking here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url=). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns.
